Miller, Dolores ILGWU and Other Publications 6036/091 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Dolores Miller ILGWU and Other Publications
1936-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Miller, Dolores
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
6036/091 PUBS
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Publications.
8594987
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 24, 2015
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 24, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6036/091 AV: Dolores Miller ILGWU Audio-Visual Materials 6036/091 MB: Dolores Miller ILGWU Memorabilia 6036/091 P: Dolores Miller ILGWU Photographs
8594987
- ABC of Parliamentary Law (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: ABC of Parlimentary Law, 1936; Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Educational Department
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
- America's Great, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: America's Great, 1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Gene Moss
- Crisis of US Capitalism, Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The Crisis of U.S. Capitalism and the Fight-Back, 1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: Gus Hall
- Diary of a Strike, Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Diary of a Strike, 1982; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Author: Bernard Karsh
- Great Traditions in Ethics, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Great Traditions in Ethics, 1969; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Author: Ethel M. Albert, Theodore C. Denise, Sheldon P. Peterfreund
- A Guide to Basic Law and Procedures under the National Labor Relations Act, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: A Guide to Basic Law Procedures Under the National Labor Relations Act, 1978; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: National Labor Relations Board, Office of the General Counsel
- Illinois Dept. of Labor Brochures, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Unemployment Insurance, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 2: The State of Illinois Information Directory, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Governor's Office of Interagency Cooperation
- Illinois State Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations - Proceedings, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Proceedings Eighteenth Annual Convention, 1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Illinois State Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations
- ILGWU News clippings, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: ILGWU Newsclippings, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
- ILGWU News clippings, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: ILGWU Newsclippings, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
- ILGWU Summer School, 1981; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Summer School Pamphlets, 1981; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Handbook of Trade Union Methods, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Handbook of Trade Union Methods, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Author: ILGWU Educational Department
- Labor Law for the Union Officer, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Labor Law for the Union Officer, 1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Duane Beeler
- Look for the Union Label, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Look for the Union Label, 1995; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Gus Tyler
    Notes: A History of the ILGWU
- Moving Forward Together, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Moving Forward Together, 1995; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Author: ILGWU General Executive Board
- Out of the Sweatshop, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Out of the Sweatshop, 1977; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Author: Leon Stein
- Pamphlets on History of Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: "This Union Cause", 1977; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: UAW Education Department
    Notes: An Illustrated History of Labor Unions in America
  - Item 2: History of the Sewing Machine, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Author: James Parton
  - Item 3: A Brief History of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
- A Pictorial History of American Labor, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: A Pictorial History of American Labor, 1972; Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Author: William Cahn
- Preparing and Presenting Your Arbitration Case, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Preparing and Presenting Your Arbitration Case, 1979; Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Author: Allan J. Harrison
    Notes: A Manual for Union and Management Representatives
- Primer of Labor Relations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Primer of Labor Relations, 1975; Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Author: Howard J. Anderson
    Notes: A Guide to Employer-Employee Conduct
- Progressive Sewing Room, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: The Progressive Sewing Room, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Author: Bertrand Frank
  - Item 2: The Progressive Sewing Room, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Report of the General Executive Board, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Report of the General Executive Board to the 34th Convention, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Author: ILGWU
  - Item 2: Report of the General Executive Board to the 34th Convention, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Report of the General Executive Board, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Report of the General Executive Board to the 35th Convention, 1974; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 2: Report of the General Executive Board to the 35th Convention, 1974; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Scarcity, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Scarcity: A Critique of the American Economy, 1976; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Songbooks, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Song Book, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Author: AFL-CIO Union Label and Service Trades Department
    Notes: 3 copies
  - Item 2: Song Book, 1974; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Author: AFL- CIO Department of Education
  - Item 3: Steelworkers' Song Book, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Author: United Steelworkers of America AFL-CIO-CLC
  - Item 4: Sing-A-Long with the ILGWU, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 5: Everybody Sings, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 6: Everybody Sings, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 7: Packet of Union Songs, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Spokesman for Labor and Socialism, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Eugene V. Debs: Spokesman for Labor and Socialism, 1978; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Author: Bernard J. Brommel
- Story of a Steward, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The Story of a Steward, 1980; Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Author: Terrence F. Connors
- A Summary Report of the Seventeenth AFL-CIO, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: A Summary Report of the Seventeenth AFL-CIO National Converence on Community Services, 1974; Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Author: AFL-CIO
- Talks with Stewards [2 copies], Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Talks with Stewards, 1966; Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Notes: 2 copies
- Thirty Five Years of the Northeast Department ILGWU, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Thirtyfive Northeast: A Short History of the Northeast Department, 1970; Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Author: Harry Crone, ILGWU, AFL-CIO
- Triangle Fire [2 copies], Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: The Triangle Fire, 1962; Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Union Professional - The Staff Rep in Action, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: The Staff Rep in Action, 1977; Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Union Representative, Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: How to be a More Effective Union Representative, 1965; Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Author: Duane Beeler & Harry Kurshenbaum
- What They Wore, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Unions, Workers, and the Law, 1983; Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Author: Betty W. Justice
- Your Money's Worth, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: What they Wore: Highlights of Fashion History, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Author: ILGWU AFL-CIO, Leon Stein